A Finding Aid to the Gustave Harrow legal records relating to the Estate of Mark Rothko AAA.harrgust2
Archives of American Art
Gustave Harrow legal records relating to the Estate of Mark Rothko
1957-1986
AAA.harrgust2
Archives of American Art
34.2 Linear feet
The Gustave Harrow legal records relating to the Estate of Mark Rothko measure 34.2 linear feet and date from 1957-1986. The records document the case brought by the New York State Attorney General's Office as cross-petitioner to the case brought by Rothko's daughter Kate, against the executors of Rothko's estate, Frank Lloyd and the Marlborough Gallery, for mismanagement and self-dealing. There are also records related to Harrow's writings about the case. Lastly, included in the collection are materials relating to art law issues in connection with the Metropolitan Museum of Art.
Harrow, Gustave
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged in 7 series.
Series 1: General Files, 1957-1981, undated
Series 2: Motions, 1971-1979, undated
Series 3: Decisions, 1970-1979, undated
Series 4: Appeals Documents, 1972-1979, undated
Series 5: Miscellaneous Case and Post-Trial files, 1972-1984, undated
Series 6: Reference Materials, Notes and Writings, 1970-1986
Series 7: Metropolitan Museum of Art / Walter Annenberg Etc., 1971-1981, undated
Biographical/Historical note
Gustave Harrow was a New York State Assistant Attorney General, and an adjunct professor in the Graduate Program in Arts Administration at NYU. Abstract Expressionist Artist Mark Rothko committed suicide February 25, 1970 leaving the bulk of his estate, including 798 paintings (the greater part of his life's work) to the Mark Rothko Foundation which he had created shortly before his death. His daughter Kate [Rothko Prizel] brought suit against the estate executors and Marlborough Gallery for self-dealing, fraud, and conspiring with Marlborough owner, Frank Lloyd to waste the assets of the estate. The state of New York Attorney General's Office, represented by Harrow, joined the case as a cross-petitioner on behalf of the people of New York's interest as beneficiaries of the charitable Foundation. The case resulted in the return of most of the paintings, the removal of the executors (accountant Bernard Reis, artist Theodoros Stamos, and anthropology professor Morton Levine), and a $9.2 million judgment against them and Frank Lloyd. The case had a lasting effect on laws dealing with artists' estates, and Harrow was instrumental in framing a bill that aimed at reducing fraud in the fine arts market. Harrow wrote about the Rothko Estate case in several articles and in the 1979 book Art, the Artist, and the Consequences of Rothko: Lasting Legal Impressions from the Estate of Great Artist.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Use of archival audiovisual recording with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice. Contact Reference services for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Gustave Harrow legal records relating to the Estate of Mark Rothko were donated to the Archives of American Art by Marilynn Karp March 23, 1996. Mr. Harrow had deposited the papers with Ms. Karp, a colleague of Harrow's at New York University where he was an adjunct professor.
Scope and Contents note
New York State Attorney General Gustave Harrow's records relating to the Estate of Mark Rothko consist of legal and other documentation of the state's case in connection with the Mark Rothko Estate and Foundation, from Surrogate Court through appeals, as well as from Harrow's writings about the case, both during and after the trial. Various trial documents include affidavits, briefs, EBTs (examination before trial) trial transcripts, motions, depositions, notes and clippings, and miscellaneous records related to the case and post-trial activities. Also found are reference materials, Harrow's writings in connection with the case.
Unrelated to the Rothko case are Harrow's research materials for possible legal actions by the state in connection with Walter Annenberg's proposed donation of a Communication Center to the Metropolitan Museum of Art, and with other issues including donations, object authenticity and the Packard Collection.
Separated Materials note
Another small collection (11 items) of Mark Rothko papers were loaned to the Archives for microfilming on reel 3135. The papers were in the possession of George Carson, husband of Rothko's ex-wife Edith Carson. Carson gave the papers to the Mark Rothko Foundation and gave the Archives of American Art permission to microfilm them. The microfilm is available at Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan but are not described in the container listing of this finding aid.
Related Archival Materials note
Among the holdings of the Archives of American Art are the Mark Rothko Foundation records, 1976-1987; Legal records relating to Richard Serra v. United States General Services Administration et al., 1985-1987.
The Archives of American Art interviewed multiple artists as part of the Mark Rothko and His Times Oral History Project. Many of the interviews reference Rothko and his work, and relationships with the artist.
The Legal records relating to Richard Serra v. United States General Services Administration et al., 1985-1987 contains documentation of another lawsuit handled by Gustave Harrow.
Annenberg, Walter H., 1908-; Mark Rothko Foundation; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.).; New York (State). Attorney General's Office.; Rothko, Mark, 1903-1970; Artists--Legal status, laws, etc.--United States; Decedents' estates--New York (State); Law and art--United States; Transcripts
- General files, 1957-1981; Series 1; 23.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-24
  Arrangement note
  Arranged in original numbered order; folder titles were transcribed exactly from original folders
  Scope and Contents note
  General files consists of documentation of both the Surrogate Court trial and the appeals. Included are correspondence, memos, affidavits, briefs, trial transcripts, depositions, examinations before trial, exhibits, motions, subpoenas, appendices, and hand-written notes. There are also reference materials including exhibition catalogs and valuation materials. Researchers may wish to consult Box 1 containing an index to general files in five card file boxes; there are also hand-written indices in the first folder of the series.
  - Index, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Index, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Index, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Index, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Index, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General File Index - Listing, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Rothko - FR. 9.1.76 FF Correspondnece - Memos etc. - Gen. Diary Note 3.24.76-9.21.76, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Diary Rothko 10.4.74-1.16.75, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Current Correspondence & Notes II, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Rothko Diary Notes - Areas, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Lee Seldes, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Lee, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Post-Sick Letters & Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous & Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - General Notes, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Diary - Rothko, Mark - Surrogate Court NY Co. 11.25.71 - Exec. Acct., 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Tel Cons Etc., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Memos - LFL & D.A. - Subpoena MBG Sometime after Toronto & Paris, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Legacy", 1978 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
  - Oliver Moore, 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Goldenberg - Wildenstein, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Taxes Schwartz Ltr about B Paintings, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Exclusive, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Motion to Dismiss PET Guardian Rothko, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - NY Supreme Court Appellate Division - /First Dept. - Brief on Appeal Lack of Jurisdiction, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Briefs - Jurisdiction, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Our Papers Injunction - Misc. Affadavits, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Injunctions - Attorney General Appendix, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Brief in Behalf of Petioner-Respondent Kate Rothko - Response to Briefs of Marlborough AG and Marlborough Gallery, Reis, Stamos..., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Gallery Fees, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Motion to Deliver Paintings, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Marlborough's First Answers to Interrogatories - Attorney General's Appendix, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - EBT - Reis - Notes, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Motions - Attorney General - Lloyd EBT, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Motions - Referee, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - EBT of Attorney General, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Motions - Marlborough - N.Y. Times, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Corrections to EBTs, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Right of Election, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "Contents" Exhibits EBTS, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Deposition of Clinton Wilder, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Index to Reis Digest, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Petition for Determination as to Construction of Certain Personal Property, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Contents - Petition Construction Disposition Personal Property, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Contents - Appendices, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Contents, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - EBTs - General, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Peterson - Sandberg's Exhs 317-349 Unmarked Duplicates, 1968-1973 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - "Old" Stock Book - Complete, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Travelling Show Insurance Berlin, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "New" Stock Book - Complete, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Marlborough Galleries Sales Receipts, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Ollendorf, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Shipping Docs, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Catalog Nos. at Exhibits, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ross "Contempt" Papers, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Insurance - Schunck & AFF.DTW Fischer, 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Trip to London - Notebooks, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fischer, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Cons. Sold - W Slide Nos. (EX.20) & Cat Nos., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "100" w/Slide Nos. & with Names (no cat. nos.), 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Slide Lists & Looseleaf Slides & Those not in Levin's, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Slides not in Inventory, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Inventories with Slide Nos. - For Experts, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Loose-Leaf Slides w/Cat. Nos., 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Slide Lists, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Rothko Catalogs, 1961-1970 (Box 4, Folder 19-20)
  - Rothko Slides, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 21-22)
  - Marlborough - Rothko Catalogs, 1971, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Rothko, 1960-1962, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - For Wald, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Janis Catalogs, 1963, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - MOMA - INS, List & Cat., 1961 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1960 etc. MOMA Cats. - Exhs. 164, 165, 150, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - P.B. Sale - $190,000 5.27.76, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Recent Sales of Rothkos & Values, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1975 - Auction Stock Market Brief - Appendix "C" (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Revised "Totals" (from Isaac) & Notes, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - #152 A,B,C - "Totals", 1974 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - #153 Estimates - 100, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Three Reports on Importance & Cond. & MISE, 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Art Prices & Rothko Prices - Memo, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Artists Contracts, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Clippings on Price Curves, 1963-1974 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Article on Curves & Prices (Goldberg), 1955-1973 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Articles on Rothko, 1957-1973 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Notes on Art - General, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Beyeler, 1969-1976 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Feigen, 1969-1972 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Rhinehardt, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Rubin, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Moffett - Schwartz - Plaut - Breem, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Wm. Rubin, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Examination of Bial, 973 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Karelsen - Examination of, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Examiation of Marla Levine, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Levine, Morton H. - Examination of, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Lloyd, Francis K. - Examination of, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 6-9)
  - McKinney, Donald S.- Examination of, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - McKinney, Donald - Examination of, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  - Schwartz, Samuel M.; Plaut, Richard L.; Moffett, Marian - Examinations of, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Reis, Bernard J. - Examination of, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - Saidenberg, Daniel - Examination of, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Stamos, Theodoros - Examination of, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Swetlitz, Morton E. - Examination of, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Wilder, Clinton - Examination of, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
  - Appendix to Brief of Marlborough Gallery & Marlborough AG and Francis Lloyd Vols I through V - Trial Transcript, 1971-1976 (Box 8, Folder 6-10)
  - Appendix to Brief of Marlborough Gallery & Marlborough AG and Francis Lloyd Vols VI through XII, 1971-1976 (Box 9, Folder 1-7)
  - Appendix in behalf of...Kate Rothko Vol I and Vol II - Trial Exhibits, 1966-1973 (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
  - Appendix in Behalf of...Kate Rothko Vol III Trial Exhibits, 1966-1973 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Appendix in Behalf of...Kate Rothko Vol IV Trial Transcript; Examination, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Trial Transcript [? first page missing], undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Beyeller, Ernst - Transcript, undated (Box 10, Folder 4-7)
  - Glimcher, Arnold, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
  - McKinney, Donald - Transcripts, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
  - McKinney, Donald - Transcripts, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Heller, Ben - Transcript, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Lloyd, Francis - Trial Transcript, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 3-10)
  - Lloyd, Francis - Trial Transcripts, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 1-10)
  - Lloyd, Francis - Trial Transcripts, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
  - Lloyd Testimony re Paris, 1975, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Shapiro, Meyer [?] - Trial Transcript, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Panicali, Carla - Trial Transcript, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 5-8)
  - James LeBron; Gertrude Stein; Rebecca Reis; Benjamin A. Heller; Meyer Schapiro; David Peck - Transcripts - End of Trial, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
  - Index to Exhibits, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Exhibits 1-5, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Exhibits 6-12, 1963-1972 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Exhibit 13, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Exhibits 14-29, 1970-1973 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Exhibits30-39, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Exhibits 40-49, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Exhibits 51, 53-55, 58-60, 62-63, 65-69, 1970-1974 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Exhibits 70-84, 86-89, 1969-1972 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Exhibits 91-94, 96-99, 102, 104-106, 1969-1974 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Exhibits 110-115, 1970-1973 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Exhibits 116-129, 1970-1974 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Exhibits 130-137, 138-149, 1969-1974 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Exhibit 150, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Exhibits 151-154, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Exhibit 155, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Exhibits 156-163, 1966-1974 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Exhibit 164, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Exhibit 165 - New American Painting, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Exhibits 166-179, 1961-1974 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Exhibits 180-189, 191-192, 1970-1974 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Exhibits 193-204, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Exhibit 205, 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Exhibit 206, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Exhibits 210 & 212, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Exhibits 214-215, 217, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Exhibit 218, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Exhibits 219, 220, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Exhibits 221-222, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Exhibit 223, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Exhibits 224-229, 1969, undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Exhibits 230-234, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Exhibit 235, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Exhibits 236-246, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Exhibits 247, 249-259, 1969-1974 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Exhibits 260-261, 263-279, 1968-1974 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Exhibits280-299, 1971-1974 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Exhibits 300-307, 309-319, 1970-1974 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Exhibits 320-329, 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Exhibits 330-339, 1972-1974 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Exhibits 340-349, 1972-1974 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Exhibits 350-359, 1971-1974 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Exhibits 360-369, 1971-1974 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Exhibits 370-375 and 377-379, 1971-1974 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Exhibits 380-391, 393-399, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Exhbits 400-409, 1970-1973 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Exhibit 410, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Exhibit 411-419, 1965-1972 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Exhibit 420-429, 1967-1971 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Exhibits 430-439, 1971-1974 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Exhibits 440-459, 1971-1974 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Exhibits 460-462, 464-469, 1970-1974 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Exhibits 470-473, 479, 1971-1974 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Exhibits 491-493, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Exhibits 504, 506, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Exhibit 507, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Exhibits 509-519, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Exhibits 520-529, 1970-1974 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Exhibits 530-547, 549-559, 1970-1974 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Exhibits 560-571, 576, 578, 579, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Exhibit 580, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Exhibits 581, 582A, 584, 586-599, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Exhibits 600-606, 608-619, 1972-1974 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Exhibits 620-639, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Exhibits 640, 642, 644-647, 649-651, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Exhibits 663-669, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Exhibits 670-674, 676-679, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Exhibits 680-699, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Exhibits 700-708, 710-719, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Exhibits 720-725, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Exhibits 730-739, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Exhibits 740-749, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Exhibits 750-762, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Exhibits 764-779, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Exhibit 780, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Exhibits 781-789, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Exhibits 790, 792-803, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Exhibits 805, 806, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Exhibits 829-833, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Exhibit 844B, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Exhibits 862, 864-869, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Exhibits 870, 872-876, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Trial Notes - Rulings; Stamos, Glimcher, Beyeler; Bial; Levine, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Jim's Brief, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Digest of Heller Trial Testimony, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Index to Levine Trial Testimony, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Index to Mckinney Trial Digest, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Index to Stamos Trial Testimony, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Digest of Beyeler Trial Testimony, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Digest of Lloyd Trial Testimony, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Digest of Panicali Trial Testimony, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Digest of Samuels Trial Testimony, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Digest of Selz Trial Testimony, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Dix, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Index to Bial Trial Digest, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Index to Levine Deposition, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Index to Levine Trial Testimony, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Index to Lloyd Digest, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Index to Stamos Trial Testimony, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Proposals, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Settlement, 1972-1974 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Trial Notes & Negotiations, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Negotiations, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Feb. '69 Sale K [Settlement Proposal], 1970 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Trial Course, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Trial Outlines, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Trial Exhibits 1-99 Index, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Petitioners' Brief, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - S. Midonick & Trial, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 28-29)
  - Settlement Talks & Memos, 1973-1974 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Pre-Trial - Order & Memos - For Trial, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Meyer's Fee, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Outline of Preparation for Rothko Trial, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Subpoenas - Mellon, Paul, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Subpoenas - Sarno, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Motions to Quash & Subpoenas, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Motion to Impound, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Contempt Violation Injunction - Other Parties, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 9-10)
  - Ross - Post Trial Brief, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - General Index I - Post Trial - Memo for Northrup, 1975-1977 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Post Trial Briefs, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 13-14)
  - AG Post Trial Reply Brief, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Brief in Behalf of...Kate Rothko, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Answering Brief, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Preparation for Appeal, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Northrup Brief, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Court of Appeals - Rich. Motion New Evidence - Motion & Affadavit 1, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Court of Appeals - Rich. New Evidence - Exhibits 1A, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Court of Appeals - Rich. New Evidence Reply Affadavit 1B, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Court of Appeals - Rich. New Evidence G.H. Affadavit, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Exhibits to Affadavit of Gustave Harrow, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Reply Brief of Attorney General of N.Y., undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Court of Appeals - Rich. New Evidence - Other Affadavits 3, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Appellate Division Brief, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Court of Appeals - Briefs - Cut for Xeroxing, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Court of Appeals - Briefs - Cut on One Side, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Court of Appeals Briefs, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Brief - Morton Levine, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 12-13)
  - Supplement to Appendix to Brief of Marlborough Gallery, Marlborough AG and Francis Lloyd Vol. 1A, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Brief for Marlborough Lloyd, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Court of Appeals - Barbara Northrup Reply Brief, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Court of Appeals - Appellants Reply to Brief Reis, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Letters to Court of Appeals, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Notes - Oral Argument Court of Appeals, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - New Evidence, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - New Evidence, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Notes - Ferbos - Landais - Addresses Etc., 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Toronto - Notes & Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Receiver's Summaries, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Rothkos at Deakins - Westcott - DeLima & AEK, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Receiver's Information & Inventories, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 6-7)
  - Ollendorff Material, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Restraints - Toronto, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - MOT: Marlborough to Report Sales, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Notice of Motion to Modify Stay of Enforcement, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - A.D. MOT - Canada Records, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Motion for Stay of Enforcement, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Administrator, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 14-15)
  - Contempt Motion of Attorney General Transcript, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Motion to Re-Argue Oders Granting Stays, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Motion to Re-Argue - Marlborough Report Sales, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Appeal - Marlborough, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Appeal - Marlborough, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Pictures to be Returned, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Attorney General - Cross Appeal, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Motion 658 Pictures (+ Toronto), 1976 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Contempt - Canada - Motion, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 5-6)
  - Levine Motion - New Evidence, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 7)